# **David Watson GitHub LinkedIn**

## **Summary and Skills**

I help teams design, develop, and deploy software. My work has ranged from desktop to data center, mobile to cloud, and startups to research labs. I'm comfortable working alone, in pairs, or in teams; private or shared office; hybrid or remote, home or coworking space. I began working remotely in 1999, from Boston to Seattle.

#### **Operating Systems and Programming Languages**

I'm productive working on Linux, MacOS, and Windows. I just need a Unix-like OS - Linux, MacOS (BSD) and Windows (WSL2) qualify.

Since 2005, I've worked primarily in Python, secondarily in C++. Prior to 2005 I've worked primarily in C++, secondarily in Python.

#### Containerization and Virtualization

I've used containerization tools like Docker since 2015, Orchestration tools like Kubernetes since 2017, and virtualization tools like VMWare since 2000.

## **Databases and Methods**

PostgreSQL has been my goto database environment since 2010, since it has managed both structured and unstructured data for years.

I work in an iterative style, from napkin sketch to provisional prototype, reflecting on design and engineering, shipping, and repeating the process.

## Experience

## Software Engineering Specialist Caterpillar 2018-2020, 2021

- Contributed code and review to multiple projects within autonomy group
- Consulted with several groups on their use of docker containers and CI/CD

### Member of Technical Staff Carnegie Mellon University 2020

- Contributed to Emerging Technology Center within Software Engineering Institute
- Work included High Performance Computing, data engineering, and Human Computer Interaction

## Senior Software Developer Realpage 2016 - 2018

- Contributed code and process to software engineering team
- Implemented crawler data pipeline using Python, PostgreSQL, Docker, and Kubernetes

## VP Product Development Wellbridge Health 2015 - 2016

- Led development team through replacement of legacy prototype with new product
- Designed and implemented REST API using DRF and PostgreSQL on web and mobile

## VP Engineering Hire an Esquire 2014

- Led engineering team from rough prototype to mature product
- Refactored Python, Django, and PostgreSQL stack

#### Senior Software Developer Forever 2013 - 2014

- Contributed code from prototype to product
- Wrote Python, Flask, MongoDB prototype, productionized Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

### Senior Engineer Smash 2011 - 2012

- Contributed code to internal systems supporting daily operations
- Designed and implemented conversational text systems and REST interfaces in python

#### Software Development Manager Wellspring 2010 - 2011

- Led development team from legacy data center to SaaS virtualization
- Prototyped DevOps (CI/CD) approach using Capistrano, Mechanize, and Selenium

## Project Engineer Applied Perception 2008-2009

- Contributed code to teams working on military robotics projects (DARPA)
- Visualized XML sonar data in python, ported Microsoft C#.net Windows GUI to C++/Qt/Linux

## UI Software Engineer Nomos 2006 - 2007

- Contributed code, tests, and review to several radiation oncology software products
- Prototyped wireframes and storyboards in C++/Qt for adaptive 4D treatment planning

### Software Design Engineer MAYA Design 2004 - 2006

- Contributed design, analysis, and code across numerous consulting projects
- Coded AJAX backends in python and a wireless lighting system in C# for Philips

#### Co-Founder Cobind 2003 - 2004

- Partnered on ideation, vision, and execution of custom Linux Tools startup
- Received wide press acclaim around custom Linux products after winning Idea Foundry Fellowship

#### Senior Software Engineer MSA 2000-2003

- Contributed code, data, and deployment before and after startup acquisition
- Implemented product import systems providing Excel VBA API from spreadsheet to database

#### Member of Technical Staff CA 1995-2000

- Contributed code to Automation Point, Raveler, and CA-Unicenter products
- Coded C++ GUI code for Legent and Platinum, before and after CA acquisition

## Programmer-Analyst Mellon 1992-1995

- Contributed code to Executive Workbench asset management product
- Implemented multi-threaded, event-driven C++ GUI code on OS/2

## Programmer-Analyst USX 1990-1992

- Contributed code to internal data center systems automation
- Automated data center operations in C/HLLAPI on OS/2 from a networked PC

### **Education**

• Bachelor of Science, Duquesne University 1991